Guide to the Samuel William Dudley Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Samuel William Dudley papers
1901-1956
MS 1086
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
Correspondence, writings, printed material, and miscellanea relating to Samuel William Dudley's career as a professor of engineering at Yale University and a mechanical engineer with the Westinghouse Air Brake Company.
Dudley, Samuel William, 1879-1963
Biographical / Historical
Samuel William Dudley was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on October 18, 1879. He received the degree of Ph.B. from Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University in 1900 and M.E. In 1903. Between 1905 and 1921, he worked with Westinghouse Air Brake Company and was assistant chief engineer between 1910 and 1914. After 1914, until he left the business, he was chief engineer. He then came to Yale to be professor of mechanical engineering, a position he held until his retirement in 1948. Between 1936 and 1948, he was also dean of the Yale School of Engineering. Once retired, Dudley became professor emeritus until his death on December 24, 1963.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, printed material, and miscellanea relating to Samuel William Dudley's career as a professor of engineering at Yale University and a mechanical engineer with the Westinghouse Air Brake Company.
Engineering; Mechanical engineering; Educators; Engineers; Dudley, Samuel William, 1879-1963; Westinghouse Air Brake Company; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
    - General, 1916-1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Test results, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical profiles, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Division of Engineering, Executive Committee
    - Dockets, memos, and correspondence, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1920-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Engineering articles, 1919-1922, 1925-1933, 1944, 1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 8 - 10)
  - "Engineering at Yale"
    - 1st and 2nd drafts, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 3rd draft, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Engineering certificate, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Engineering committee
    - General, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Reorganization, 1919, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Engineering education, undated (Box 2, Folder 16 - 18)
  - Engineering Instruction Committee, 1919-1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Engineers' Council for Professional Development, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Hillyer College, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Hopkins Grammar School
    - Fund raising, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Pamphlet, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mechanical engineering thesis, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1936-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Newcomen Society of England, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - New England Council Power survey, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Report of the President's Committee, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - School of Engineering, Dean's Report, 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Westinghouse Air Brake Company
    - Correspondence, 1927-1949 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Writings, 1920, 1930, 1940, undated (Box 5, Folder 33 - 39)
    - Writings, 1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 40 - 41)
  - Writings, 1903-1934, undated (Box 6, Folder 42 - 51)
  - Writings, 1914, 1929-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 52 - 60)